#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Omar Josué Guzmán Valerín

Nationality: Costa Rican

**ID Number**: 3-0443-0305

Phone number: (506) - 61036691

Career: Systems Engineering

Birthday: February 19, 1990

Home address: Cartago, Costa Rica

Phone number: (506) - 61036691

Email: omarjo90@gmail.com

**Github**: <a href="https://github.com/omarjo90">https://github.com/omarjo90</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-josue-guzman-valerin-70742b34">https://www.linkedin.com/in/omar-josue-guzman-valerin-70742b34</a>

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Omar Josue Guzman Valerin

Quality Assurance Developer in Cartago Province, Costa Rica

Omar is a senior test automation engineer with more than 11 years of proven testing experience. He is passionate about creating test scripts in Python for front-end and back-end projects, where he was able to set up frameworks and help teams to create test strategies for manual and automation projects in Agile environments. Also, Omar has well developed IT skills combined with a flexible attitude to work.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS SUMMARY**

- Selenium Webdriver
- Cypress
- Behave
- Cucumber
- Python
- Java
- Request HTTP
   library for Python
- API testing
- API Automation testing

- UI Automation testing
- BrowserStack
- Mobile Automation testing
- Appium
- Linux
- Git
- lira
- Testrail
- Functional QA
- Scripting

- ISTQB certification 19-CTFL-166890-09
- Pytest Framework
- Postman
- Page Object Model
   Pattern
- Terraform
- Ansible
- Docker
- AWS
- GCP
- AZURE

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Sysdig - Full time

November 2022 to April 2024

# **Senior Software Developer in Test**

- Create coverage for FrontEnd automated test cases
- Create coverage for BackEnd automated test cases
- Review pull requests
- Check CI/CD pipeline to validate failed test cases
- Report bugs
- Coordinate with co-workers for new tasks
- Execute automation
- Automation of cloud infrastructure with terraform and ansible
- Cloud provider experience with GCP, AZURE and AWS
- AWS, AZURE and GCP api used to create and obtain information using the python package/library
- Conducting Functional Backend and Web Automation testing, while developing automation scripts for seamless service integration. Establishing test coverage within the codebase.
- Testing Kubernetes clusters via terminal commands, Virtual machines using CLI, and automating Backends with pytest, Python, Java's RestAssured, and Cucumber.

- Leveraging diverse operating systems for thorough validation, and implementing CI/CD pipelines for daily test executions.
- Utilizing Jenkins and Github to efficiently manage test cases, bugs, etc., and provisioning instances across AWS, GCP, AZURE, Terraform, and Ansible.

# Instawork - Full time Senior Quality Assurance Automation Engineer

## November 2021 to August 2022

- Fix mobile(iOS & Android) automated test cases
- Create mobile(iOS & Android) automated test cases
- Execute regression test to mobile(iOS & Android) app
- Execute automation against jenkins
- Execute automation against browserstack
- Automate test cases in iOS and Android
- Work in agile teams to implement new features
- Pull request reviews

# Toptal - The World's Top Talent, On Demand® Senior QA Automation Engineer

**November 2020 to Present** 

- Working as a senior test automation engineer at Toptal.
- Create frontend automated test cases for <a href="https://fiscalnote.com">https://fiscalnote.com</a>.
- Track and manage automation tickets to increase coverage for the Export Module/Feature.
- Create jira tickets to automate test cases.
- Pull requests reviews.
- GIT
- Pytest
- Python
- Selenium
- Docker
- BrowserStack
- Profile: https://www.toptal.com/resume/omar-josue-guzman-valerin

# Gorilla Logic, Costa Rica Senior QA Automation Engineer

### March 2018 - October 2021

- Built a back-end framework in Python to execute API test cases and add its results to TestRail using Jenkins for CI.
- Developed a front-end framework in Python to execute automated test cases and return detailed error messages if the test case fails and pictures when it failed.
- Delivered with results, a good quality project that finished its development process, and the client was very happy with the application's quality.
- Created documents for transfer knowledge of the project and helped new people on the team understand how to test the application and how it works.
- Selenium automation for front-end projects

# Softon Digital, Costa Rica Quality Assurance Analyst

**November 2017 - March 2018** 

- Coordinate status and updates for the project tasks
- Test cases creation
- Test case verification
- Create Regression test plans
- Manual and Exploratory testing
- Agile methodology
- Automation
- User story testing
- Functional testing
- Constantly communication with the Project Owner of the project in order to get clarification on requirements

Growth Acceleration Partners, Costa Rica Mid QA Engineer

February 2014 - October 2017

- Lead and owned an important software feature.
- Created and developed installation, uninstallation, and update shell scripts for this feature.
- Created test plans and served as the main point of contact for this feature.
- Helped and trained new team members that were onboarding process.
- API testing and automation
- Front-end automation with Selenium
- Bug triage

# Testing Software, Costa Rica Quality Engineer

February 2012 - 2014

- Delivered test plans and manual test cases for projects.
- Learned automation skills using Java and started using Selenium.
- Provided feedback to the co-workers in the USA in order to test the project.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Bachelor's degree in System Engineering Universidad Latina Costa Rica 2008 2012
- Appium and Selenium with Python From Basics to Framework OCTOBER 2021 -PRESENT
   Udemy
- Performance Testing Course with JMeter and Blazemeter OCTOBER 2020 -

**PRESENT** 

Udemy

• Django 3 - Full Stack Websites with Python Web Development JUNE 2020 -

**PRESENT** 

**Udemy** 

- Elegant Automation Frameworks with Python and Pytest APRIL 2020 PRESENT
   Udemy
- ISTQB Certified Tester Foundation Level (CTFL) NOVEMBER 2019 PRESENT
   ISTQB
- 2020 Complete Python Bootcamp: From Zero to Hero in Python JULY 2018 -

**PRESENT** 

**Udemy**